<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Acta on NetSec</title>
    <link>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Acta on NetSec</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Acta #018</title>
      <link>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2021-018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2021-018/</guid>
      <description>Secure (S)Hell: Introducing an SSH Deception Proxy Framework
(preprint) Cryptography and Security (cs.CR) 2021 [PDF, INFO]
 Deceiving an attacker in the network security domain is a well established approach, mainly achieved through deployment of honeypots consisting of open network ports with the sole purpose of raising an alert on a connection. With attackers becoming more careful to avoid honeypots, other decoy elements on real host systems continue to create uncertainty for attackers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acta #017</title>
      <link>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2021-017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2021-017/</guid>
      <description>Can You Accept LaTeX Files from Strangers? Ten Years Later
(preprint) Cryptography and Security (cs.CR) 2021 [PDF, INFO]
 It is well-known that Microsoft Word/Excel compatible documents or PDF files can contain malicious content. LaTeX files are unfortunately no exception either. LaTeX users often include third-party codes through sources or packages (.sty or .cls files). But those packages can execute malicious commands on the users&#39; system, in order to capture sensitive information or to perform denial of service attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acta #015</title>
      <link>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2021-015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2021-015/</guid>
      <description>The CNAME of the Game: Large-scale Analysis of DNS-based Tracking Evasion
Privacy Enhancing Technologies 2021 [PDF, INFO]
 Online tracking is a whack-a-mole game between trackers who build and monetize behavioral user profiles through intrusive data collection, and anti-tracking mechanisms, deployed as a browser extension, built-in to the browser, or as a DNS resolver. As a response to pervasive and opaque online tracking, more and more users adopt anti-tracking tools to preserve their privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acta #014</title>
      <link>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2021-014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2021-014/</guid>
      <description>CADE: Detecting and Explaining Concept Drift Samples for Security Applications
USENIX Security &amp;lsquo;21 [PDF, INFO]
 Concept drift poses a critical challenge to deploy machine learning models to solve practical security problems. Due to the dynamic behavior changes of attackers (and/or the benign counterparts), the testing data distribution is often shifting from the original training data over time, causing major failures to the deployed model.
To combat concept drift, we present a novel system CADE aiming to 1) detect drifting samples that deviate from existing classes, and 2) provide explanations to reason the detected drift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acta #013</title>
      <link>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2021-013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2021-013/</guid>
      <description>Its all in a name: detecting and labeling bots by their name Computational and Mathematical Organization Theory (2018) [PDF, INFO]
 Automated social media bots have existed almost as long as the social media environments they inhabit. Their emergence has triggered numerous research efforts to develop increasingly sophisticated means to detect these accounts. These efforts have resulted in a cat and mouse cycle in which detection algorithms evolve trying to keep up with ever evolving bots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acta #012</title>
      <link>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2021-012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2021-012/</guid>
      <description>Designing Actively Secure, Highly Available Industrial Automation Applications 17th International Conference on Industrial Informatics (INDIN2019) [PDF]
 Programmable Logic Controllers (PLCs) execute critical control software that drives Industrial Automation and Control Systems (IACS). PLCs can become easy targets for cyber-adversaries as they are resource-constrained and are usually built using legacy, less-capable security measures. Security attacks can significantly affect system availability, which is an essential requirement for IACS. We propose a method to make PLC applications more security-aware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acta #011</title>
      <link>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2021-011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2021-011/</guid>
      <description>Keystone: An Open Framework for Architecting Trusted Execution Environments
Proceedings of the Fifteenth European Conference on Computer Systems (EuroSys) 2020 [PDF, Info Slides]
Abstract
 Trusted execution environments (TEEs) see rising use in devices from embedded sensors to cloud servers and encompass a range of cost, power constraints, and security threat model choices. On the other hand, each of the current vendor-specific TEEs makes a fixed set of trade-offs with little room for customization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acta #010</title>
      <link>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2021-010/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2021-010/</guid>
      <description>How China Detects and Blocks Shadowsocks
Internet Measurement Conference (IMC) 2020 [PDF, Info]
Abstract
 Shadowsocks is one of the most popular circumvention tools inChina. Since May 2019, there have been numerous anecdotal reportsof the blocking of Shadowsocks from Chinese users. In this study,we reveal how the Great Firewall of China (GFW) detects and blocksShadowsocks and its variants. Using measurement experiments,we find that the GFW uses the length and entropy of the first datapacket in each connection to identify probable Shadowsocks traffic,then sends seven different types of active probes, in different stages,to the corresponding servers to test whether its guess is correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acta #009</title>
      <link>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2021-009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2021-009/</guid>
      <description>Timeless Timing Attacks: Exploiting Concurrency to Leak Secrets over Remote Connections
29th USENIX Security Symposium, 2020 [PDF, Info]
Abstract
 To perform successful remote timing attacks, an adversarytypically collects a series of network timing measurementsand subsequently performs statistical analysis to reveal a dif-ference in execution time. The number of measurements thatmust be obtained largely depends on the amount of jitter thatthe requests and responses are subjected to. In remote tim-ing attacks, a significant source of jitter is the network pathbetween the adversary and the targeted server, making it prac-tically infeasible to successfully exploit timing side-channelsthat exhibit only a small difference in execution time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acta #008</title>
      <link>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2020-008/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2020-008/</guid>
      <description>The agenda:
 Malialis, K., &amp;amp; Kudenko, D. (2015). Distributed response to network intrusions using multiagent reinforcement learning. Engineering Applications of Artificial Intelligence, 41, 270&amp;ndash;284. doi:10.1016/j.engappai.2015.01.013 [sci-hub link] Tomic, I., &amp;amp; McCann, J. A. (2017). A Survey of Potential Security Issues in Existing Wireless Sensor Network Protocols. IEEE Internet of Things Journal, 4(6), 1910&amp;ndash;1923. doi:10.1109/jiot.2017.2749883 [sci-hub link] Krishnamurthy, P., Karri, R., &amp;amp; Khorrami, F. (2019). Anomaly Detection in Real-Time Multi-Threaded Processes Using Hardware Performance Counters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acta #007</title>
      <link>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2020-007/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2020-007/</guid>
      <description>The agenda:
 Tor Traffic Identification Stealing, Spying, and Abusing: Consequences of Attacks on Internet of Things Devices NetChain: Scale-Free Sub-RTT Coordination  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acata #006</title>
      <link>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2019-006/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2019-006/</guid>
      <description>The agenda:
 Threat Analysis for Wearable Health Devices and Environment Monitoring Internet of Things Integration System Robustifying Network Protocols with Adversarial Examples  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acta #005</title>
      <link>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2019-005/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2019-005/</guid>
      <description>The agenda:
 An Efficient Opportunistic Routing Protocol for ICN Dynamic Optimal Countermeasure Selection for Intrusion Response System RESTful HTTPS over Zigbee: Why and how?  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acta #004</title>
      <link>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2019-004/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2019-004/</guid>
      <description>The agenda:
 Towards a Cyber Defense Framework for SCADA Systems Based on Power Consumption Monitoring Situational Awareness for security adaptation in Industrial Control Systems A Multi-Classifier Network-Based Crypto Ransomware Detection System: A Case Study of Locky Ransomware  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acta #003</title>
      <link>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2019-003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2019-003/</guid>
      <description>The agenda:
 WADI: a water distribution testbed for research in the design of secure cyber physical systems Towards Understanding Man-on-the-Side Attacks (MotS) in SCADA Networks  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acta #002</title>
      <link>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2019-002/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2019-002/</guid>
      <description>The agenda:
 Blockchain Radio Access Network (B-RAN): Towards Decentralized Secure Radio Access Paradigm A Re-evaluation of Intrusion Detection Accuracy: Alternative Evaluation Strategy Towards Malware Detection via CPU Power Consumption: Data Collection Design and Analytics  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acta #001</title>
      <link>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2019-001/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsec.just-paranoid.net/acta/2019-001/</guid>
      <description>After last weeks meeting, we decided each meeting we will discuss three papers.
The agenda:
 A Deep Learning Approach to Network Intrusion Detection Implementing Zero Trust Cloud Networks with Transport Access Control and First Packet Authentication Intelligent Security Measures for Smart Cyber-Physical Systems  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
